hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and if we haven't met yet I've
been helping coaches trainers mentors
and authors scale their businesses and
Brands to tens of millions of dollars
online for the last 19 years and I want
to help you break past what's stopping
you from growing and scaling your
business today's episode is actually all
about that how do you scale a coaching
business to 10K months that's that's a
hundred and twenty thousand dollars a
year that's a it's a pretty good income
from a coaching business especially if
you can do so working only five to ten
hours a week and our clients that's what
they experience in fact we have a client
that's made over a million dollars in
one month working just five to ten hours
a week and it's scalable it's
sustainable from the beginning
so what I want to show you how to do is
how to get started on the right foot
doing the right activities from day one
so that you don't have to struggle so
that you don't have to come back around
and say man I wish I knew this
when I got started and so that's you
today if you're not making 10K a month
in your coaching business I'm going to
give you
my key steps that you need to start
scaling your business to those 10K
months and so
what am I doing right now I am walking
around
my neighborhood because I've found
that I can actually make better podcast
episodes by simply going for a walk and
talking while I do this so come along
with me come along on this journey
when I started my coaching business
I was in a unique situation because
I had been working with my mom
we had skilled her business to over 20
million dollars
and my experience was as CEO I also did
all the marketing I did all the
advertising I wrote all the emails I
wrote all the sales copy I was creating
all the ideas for the products
basically everything that she wasn't
doing what was my mom doing my mom was
showing up on camera teaching the
content and actually being the face of
the brand and I was the one kind of the
man behind the curtain running all the
stuff behind the scenes and when I
started my business
I didn't realize how hard it was to
actually get results of the scale to ten
thousand a month in fact my coaching and
course business only made about
two grand a month
some months only a thousand bucks a
month from coaching courses for like
three years
and I was dealing with even imposter
syndrome like man I know what it takes
to scale these coaching businesses in
fact during that time
we had a client his name was Rick Pino
he's the one that was making over a
million dollars a month we helped him
scale
from his initial launch was about six
thousand a month all the way up to a
million dollars a month in four years
and I'm like okay I've helped all these
people do it
why can't I seem to do it myself
and actually that was one of the biggest
factors for me for scaling was I had to
make myself a priority
I had to make my business a priority I
had to say okay I love Rick
I love the clients I work with
but I have to make me important not them
and that is hard to do especially if
you've been trained as a pleaser as a
people pleaser if you've grown up to
where making other people happy
equals your self-worth and that's how I
grew up
and a performance for love type
environment where if I perform well then
I'm that I'm worthy of love then I'm
worthy of acceptance and a lot of people
grow up in that
and so that's one of the first things
setting boundaries and learning to
manage your time to put yourself first
before other people
we have messages in our culture and our
society that tell us to not do this to
not put ourselves first to put other
people first
when it comes to you being an
entrepreneur
you have to put yourself first
you have to make yourself the Supreme
priority
or you will not grow your business and
this is one of the number one reasons
why
people think that
it's too hard to build a business
because they're actually just afraid
they're terrified of being judged by
their friends being judged by their
family as being too selfish
so that's one of the first things
that I've seen and and here's the truth
when you are a little bit more selfish
for yourself
you're actually gonna be able to take
care of others better here's a perfect
example of that by me making myself a
priority we were able to grow our
business
to multiple six figures
and now I'm able to hire help around the
house so that I don't have to spend time
working around the house doing stuff
around the house because we have people
in our house that are helping do stuff
and so by making me a priority our
business grows and scales and so that's
one of the first things is making you
a priority now the second one is this
promotion
promoting your business
too many coaches and course creators
don't promote their business enough
they're not putting themselves out there
enough
they're not making offers enough
they're not advertising offers for
people to get on their email list enough
and this is why they don't have clients
in their business they're just expecting
people to say well you're a good coach
they're expecting people to buy osmosis
be like well you got this coaching thing
you got this course I'm going to come to
you when I need it and everybody's going
to show up because you're an amazing
person and that's not reality that's a
fantasy that doesn't exist
and so when I started promoting my
business when I started like actually
working through the six steps
that we talk about
finding your Niche is Step number one
okay
and the only reason people get stuck on
finding their niche
is because they're afraid of it not
being good enough they're afraid of it
not producing result pick something and
start there
don't let fear
run your life anymore you cannot allow
fear to dictate your choices in your
life and your business
and a lot of people allow fear to stop
them from even picking a niche and so
then it's like well how are you gonna
build a coaching business you don't even
know what you're going to coach on and
they're afraid of choosing the wrong
thing
this often comes from being
either punished because they made a
mistake
fear of making mistakes fear of messing
up
or
could be if you have a religious
background
that you're like well I don't want to
take the wrong path it'll lead to
destruction right I don't want to miss
the mark in my business and this
thinking we got to get rid of this
thinking and rip it out of our head
because it's not serving us it's not
serving you and it's not serving those
that you can help
by operating in that way
and so pick something as your niche
one of the best ways to decide an inch
is to go on Amazon and look up
you know
what other people in that Niche what
what books are out there
what topics are they sharing on and then
the next step is writing your offer copy
that's not planning it's not mapping out
your coaching program
this is where most coaches and course
creators get it wrong as they spend so
much energy
mapping out their coaching programs
planning out their course
planning out their training coming up
with
what like trying to be an excellent
coach when the fact is you can't do that
unless you got people to coach you can't
do that unless you got people to
actually teach unless you got people to
actually
buy your courses and so a lot of people
are literally just guessing and spending
I I know a lady right now she's now on
year seven of mapping out her course and
every time I talk to her she says I'm
laying the foundations down I'm getting
the foundations I'm getting the
foundations going I'm sorry but you've
been getting the foundations going for
this long and I got clients that are
making millions of dollars the whole
time that you've been sitting around
coming up with the foundations
and I don't mean that to be harsh
but honestly that's more tied to and
connected to Mental Health
than actually a lack of strategy
it's more tied to worry and fear and
possibly trauma and unresolved trauma
the inability to actually make decisions
and the fear of making the wrong
decision
than actually having a lack of strategy
is why that is and and unfortunately
this lady is not receptive to that
um I've I've shared this numerous times
she's just no Jeremiah it's just I gotta
I gotta gotta be perfect gotta be
perfect gotta be perfect I'm sorry but
perfectionism is also tied to
many times
unresolved trauma and abuse
it's not a spirit of Excellence it's not
a spirit of of being outstanding at your
work it's fear and insecurity and worry
that you will get punished that things
will go wrong that you will get hurt
that you'll waste time and you'll waste
money if things aren't perfect
imperfect action is what produces
results
launching imperfectly
not worrying about looking good to other
people
not concerning yourself about
being perfect and just putting offers
out there and so what I teach people to
do is you come up with your Niche and
then you write offer copy you come up
with the offer copy based around what
your Target customer wants and you build
something to capture their name and
email address
and and by doing that
you then what we like to do is we use
Virtual events to where if you're doing
like a a one-day event like I did this
past weekend
or you might do a three-day event around
a specific topic that you're coaching on
around your Niche around the result that
the person is actually wanting and what
this does is this gives you an
opportunity to actually then sell to
your prospects to actually make a sales
presentation to people if you're not
getting people's eyeballs in front of
you
to make a sales presentation
how do you expect them to buy from you
you're not Apple computer they spend
billions on Advertising
you're not Microsoft
your business and your branding is not
going to be awesome enough to get people
to just make a decision to become your
customer simply because you're just
awesome and amazing so you have to
actually promote and then sell and get
people in front of you
get people to actually show up in front
of you to where you can present to them
a sales pitch and then sell them on your
coaching and your courses and we
recommend that you do at least a
thousand dollars as the price point in
this economy you have to do it at least
a thousand dollars or you're devaluing
yourself
and and this is where people get stuck
in their brain because they're like well
I don't have anything of value enough to
charge a thousand dollars for because
they're comparing themselves to other
people and they're allowing stupid
academic teaching to tell them that
they're not worth being paid that much
and they're allowing this belief that
they need to become more enlightened to
a certain level before they're good
enough to be able to charge that much
and I'm here to say that's a complete
lie you don't need to be an expert
to make six figures as a coach
you don't need to be an expert to make
the kind of money that you want to make
you just need to know a little bit more
than somebody else who's a little bit
further behind you
on the path that they're on
and then
get a bunch of those people in front of
you
sell to them an opportunity
for the results and by the way you can't
guarantee the result nobody can because
you can't guarantee that they're
actually going to take action and so get
that out of your brain
that you need to make sure that you can
guarantee a result before you can sell
it
this isn't a matter of Integrity this is
called business
get it out of your brain
that you have to be able to make
Perfection happen
the fantasy idea
that unless you can make people
become your customer that unless you can
make people
do what you want that I can't Market I
can't sell and I can't make an offer
this belief that it's your job
to make people do what they should and
that as a coach as a course creator that
unless you can make people do what they
should that you don't have the value or
the Worth to Market to people that
belief limits people it's a complete lie
it comes from again academics it comes
from college it comes from Corporate
America where we're comparing ourselves
where we're constantly judging and
honestly when you let go of the Judgment
that you've had for other people when
you let go of the fear of judgment from
other people you let go of the fear and
worry of consequences from other people
you become an Unstoppable Force when it
comes to you marketing and selling your
coaching and courses online and so I
want to encourage you if you're somebody
that's a course creator that's a coach
that's a mentor and you're stuck and
you're saying I don't know how to scale
to six figures
address the beliefs that are limiting
you from actually doing the activities
address the beliefs in your brain
that are telling you I'm not good enough
yet to do this and I'm here to tell you
you are good enough right now as you are
you don't need to get any better now you
will improve over time that's important
to do that but you want to do that in
the process and what we recommend people
do
is pre-sell their coaching their courses
pre-sell their training before it's
finished get some clients get some
people that will give you feedback
because then that feedback loop will
allow you to actually create better
offers better marketing and attract
better clients
stop waiting until some fantasy land
moment where you got it all figured out
and it's all mapped and all planned out
and just start doing the basics just
start getting the ball rolling just
start moving the needle forward
and the rest will work itself out
now how do we actually find these people
that are going to spend money with us
how do we actually find the people that
are going to become our clients
what we run at
we use paid advertising to actually find
those people tick tock Instagram
Facebook
Twitter ads
and by doing this when you know how to
run ads the right way you're able to
train the algorithm this is why your
offer copy is so important you're able
to actually train the algorithm to show
your offer
to show your virtual event to show your
your lead magnet to show your webinar to
show your offer to the right people at
the right time
and so what it is is the algorithms are
actually going to show your offer to
people that are actually wanting what
you're putting out there
and then you don't have to worry well is
this going to show to the right people
or not because when you do it the way
that I teach you the way that I show you
the way that I work with my one-on-one
coaching clients to do you can have
confidence in knowing that you're doing
the right steps that you're following
the right order now is there a risk of
course there's a risk in anything
there's a risk of you losing money
there's a risk of it not working
there's a risk of it not producing the
results that you're actually wanting
that's part of the process of building a
business
there's no such thing as certainty in
building a business and so you got to
get rid of that BS lie that comes from
Corporate America that comes from
college
education lie Factory that tells you
that there's such thing as certainty in
business
and so and then be willing to say okay
I'm gonna take a risk
now don't run ads more than you're
willing to lose but what we recommend
people to do is
wipe out some debt off your credit card
wipe out a little bit
off your credit card so then you can run
ads with a small portion of that credit
card and then pay it back off of the
sales that come in and that's why you
need to actually sell your offers for a
thousand dollars because you're not
going to bring in enough money
if it's not a thousand bucks
you're gonna lose money
this is our experience that we are
seeing right now
and so if you want to actually make the
kind of money you want to make
if you want to actually be successful
in your business and you don't want to
struggle and and worry is this going to
work is this going to produce a result
you need to actually charge enough so
there's profit margins you need to
actually charge enough so that
when people buy from you
that there's enough to pay for your ad
spend so there's enough to pay for your
marketing see a lot of people are like
well
how do I make money without spending any
money
in the coaching and online course
business organic marketing doesn't work
the way that it used to the organic side
of doing things doesn't work the way
that it did back in 2014 back in 2012.
and so we have to start to utilize
what's in front of us now sure you can
use tick tock you can use Instagram
reels it will show your content to
people
um the algorithms will show your content
to people but they're not going to go
viral like they used to this is not
2012. this isn't 2016. this isn't 2018.
and so it starts with creating
strategic offers that people want
creating
strategic offers that people give you
their email address for and then you
solve a problem for them
at a virtual event
to where they come to an event with you
for one day
two days online on Zoom they meet you on
zoom and then you can make a sales
presentation to those people and this is
the process that we're using that's
scaling businesses to tens of millions
of dollars that'll help you scale you're
like well I don't want to make tens of
millions of dollars I just want to make
six figures I just want to make
10K a month this will help you get there
this is the process that will get you
there it's the exact same like overall
strategy works
and so
the question I'm going to ask you is
when I've been talking about these steps
why won't you do them
why aren't you doing them right now
answer those questions for yourself
why are you gonna let six to 12 months
pass you by and not do what I've talked
about
it's always always related to some kind
of a belief of inadequacy
or
I hate to say this it's Pride
your ego is so stuck so far up your butt
that you're like I could never do what
Jeremiah talked about and if that's the
case I'm surprised you're even still
listening to me at this point
but for everybody else it's always
always related to fear
it's always related to worry
it's always related to fear of how am I
going to be judged by my friends what
are people going to think about me
are people Gonna Hate Me are they gonna
ask for their money back are they gonna
get mad at me are they going to get
angry and we allow these fears to stop
us
from actually building growing and
scaling our businesses and so I want to
encourage you
stop letting your fear
run your life
stop letting worry dictate what you can
and can't do
and start to
do the steps finding your niche
writing your offer copy we use jasper.ai
to use artificial intelligence to write
the alpha copy you don't even need to be
a marketing expert to write those words
anymore you can use artificial
intelligence tools that are just as easy
to use as Microsoft Word
to actually connect with your target
Prospect
and then you create a landing page that
gets people's name and email address and
then you promote it out to people and
you sell your offers why aren't you
doing those steps
why are you not
well I don't know what to do I literally
just told you what to do so like get
more specific I don't know what to do
what does that actually mean to you
like I need you to sit with this for
yourself
I needed to actually answer that for
yourself why are you not doing this
anybody can do these steps right now
they don't need to change or grow or do
anything different in their life the
only reason people won't is because fear
and because they actually enjoy their
fear and because they're addicted to the
fear and worry in their life because
they don't know any better because they
don't know any different
and as soon as you break up with that as
soon as you say I'm going to be
intentional
to not let fear and worry control my
life I'm going to be intentional to
actually
grow my business that's when you start
to see results and that's when the magic
happens
now if you're somebody that says I want
some help with this I want you Jeremiah
to walk me through this process I want
you to show me what to do I'd love to
work with you you can join one of our
free events that we're doing
you get on the waiting list for my group
coaching program you can schedule a VIP
day where I come in and we work together
for a whole day to help you build your
business together
if this has helped you at all share this
with somebody if you know a coach a
course grader somebody trying to make
six figures online doing this share this
with them as well I think it'll really
bless them great life everybody we'll
talk soon